<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>CyberSoup</title><subtitle>Your tasty cyber security snack</subtitle> <updated>2026-01-17T04:39:18+00:00</updated> <author> <name>CyberSoup</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2026 CyberSoup </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Keycloak Selector - Easy Flow Design</title><link href="/posts/keycloak-selector/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keycloak Selector - Easy Flow Design" /><published>2026-01-04T04:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2026-01-04T04:00:00+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/keycloak-selector/</id> <content src="/posts/keycloak-selector/" /> <author> <name>michal</name> </author> <category term="Tools" /> <category term="IAM" /> <summary>Intro Keycloak is a well-established open-source Identity and Access Management (IAM) solution released under the Apache 2.0 license. It was originally developed by Red Hat and, since 2023, has been part of the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF). Keycloak is written in Java and is highly customizable. In my experience, it is also fairly easy to configure and brand. It provides the core ...</summary> </entry> <entry><title>Developer's confession, building a custom passkey authenticator</title><link href="/posts/pitfalls-passkey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Developer&amp;apos;s confession, building a custom passkey authenticator" /><published>2025-10-19T04:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2025-12-01T08:41:23+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/pitfalls-passkey/</id> <content src="/posts/pitfalls-passkey/" /> <author> <name>michalvijay</name> </author> <category term="Lessons learned" /> <summary>Intro I’ve been following the FIDO2 → passkeys story for a few years now. It started during my PhD, when I was digging into it as part of my research, and later continued at work, where I tried a few small real-world deployments—just enough to run into all the odd edge cases nobody talks about. Along the way I’ve shared what I’ve learned, given a few talks, and yes, occasionally complained ab...</summary> </entry> <entry><title>WiCyS 2025 Workshop - Phishing Resistance of Passkeys</title><link href="/posts/WICYS-workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WiCyS 2025 Workshop - Phishing Resistance of Passkeys" /><published>2025-04-05T04:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2025-04-05T04:00:00+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/WICYS-workshop/</id> <content src="/posts/WICYS-workshop/" /> <author> <name>michalnat</name> </author> <category term="Presentations" /> <summary>Intro This year at WiCyS 2025, held in Dallas, Texas, Nat and I had the pleasure of running a workshop on the last day of the conference. Despite it was the final session, the room was packed, the energy was high, and the engagement was fantastic. We’re publishing this article as a follow-up to the session—both to answer some of the recurring questions and to share the insights with those who c...</summary> </entry> <entry><title>Cybersecurity - the longest journey</title><link href="/posts/GIAC-notes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cybersecurity - the longest journey" /><published>2024-12-19T04:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2024-12-19T07:46:47+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/GIAC-notes/</id> <content src="/posts/GIAC-notes/" /> <author> <name>nat</name> </author> <category term="Lessons learned" /> <summary>Part One: The Calling Ever since I joined the ranks of IT professionals, I’ve been constantly surprised by how patchy cybersecurity awareness is in some organizations. This unfortunately translates into uneven and often inadequate security controls. As much as one might be reluctant to admit it, securing organizational assets is an uphill battle—especially when there’s never enough budget to i...</summary> </entry> <entry><title>Keeping secrets secret</title><link href="/posts/secret-zero/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keeping secrets secret" /><published>2024-12-19T04:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2024-12-19T08:51:36+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/secret-zero/</id> <content src="/posts/secret-zero/" /> <author> <name>michal</name> </author> <category term="Secrets" /> <category term="IAM" /> <summary>Introduction Software development is often seen as a blend of engineering and art — a creative process where developers work within the boundaries of project requirements, timelines, technological limitations, and team capacity. The goal? To produce human-readable code that, through various transformations, solves a specific problem. From a business standpoint, software is primarily judged by...</summary> </entry> </feed>
